Hello!
John Cameron!
Chingachgook!
How are you?
The Master of Life
is good, John.
Another year passed.
How is it
with you?
Getting along.
Yes, I am.
Nathaniel.
Hello, John. Cleared
another quarter, I see.
Yes, I did.
Alexandra.
Welcome.
Jack, how are you?
Hello, Nathaniel.
How've you been?
Good. Thank you.
Where you boys
been trapping?
West of the Cuyahoga.
Why is Uncas
with you?
He should have settled with a
woman, started a family by now.
Hey! Hey!
Hey, Uncas, look!
Mohawk field we saw was
five mile long on the river.
Chief Joseph
Brandt's field.
You take much fur?
That we did.
Lots.
The Horicon's
near trapped-out now.
Where are you trading
your skins? Castleton?
No.
Schuylerville.
Schuylerville, with
the Dutch, for silver.
French and English want to
pay with wampum and brandy.
So what is it, Jack?
What brings you here?
French and Indian army are
heading south out of Fort Carillon
to war against
the British.
I’m helping to raise New York's
militia to fill the Crown's levy.
And the people here are
gonna join in that fight?
We'll see in the morning.
Where're you boys heading?
We'll trap over the fall.
Winter in Can-tuck-ee.
Find a Delaware-speaking
woman for Uncas.
She will say, "You are the
one!" Bear him many children.
Then you can
have a boy like me.
Never.
You're too strong.
Turn me old too fast.
That's what he's
doing to his mama.
John Cameron, thank you
for your hospitality.
Mohawk traded furs
with les français.
We got no quarrel
Now les français bring Huron,
Ottawa, Abenaki onto Mohawk land.
Now Mohawk will fight
les français and Huron.
I speak for the Twin Rivers
Mohawk of the Six Nations.
His Majesty, King George II, is
very grateful for your support.
How far up the valley?
Up to Fort William Henry.
That's two nights
and a bit from here.
Should be enough to remind you
all that France is our enemy.
France is
your enemy.
What did you say?
While we're at your fort, what
if the French attack our homes?
What then, Lieutenant?
For your homes,
for King, for country!
That's why you men
ought to join this fight!
You do what you want
with your own scalp.
Do not be telling us what
we ought to do with ours.
You call yourself a patriot?
A loyal subject to the Crown?
I do not call myself
subject to much at all.
I agree with some of what
Nathaniel and John say,
but I believe England's
still our sovereign.
I’ll go.
We will go to
fight the French.
My brother and I
will volunteer up.
I’ll fight
with you, Jack.
I’m staying
on my farm.
Any man who goes,
his family's welcome
to fort up with us
till he comes back.
Boys,
my sense of it is
we have enough here
to fill the county levy,
and it's a fight
we ought to make.
But first we got to get
terms from General Webb.
Where are you
meeting him?
We'll go to Albany.
Attention!
We speak for the men,
not command them.
If they're not allowed leave to
defend their farms and families
if the French
attack the settlements,
then no colonial militia is
going to Fort William Henry.
They will report or be
pressed into service.
Any of the boys
worth having
can disappear into the
forest. They will be found.
And where does that
leave you then?
Those men will be
found, arrested...
I cannot imagine His
Majesty, in his benevolence,
would ever object to his
loyal American subjects
defending their hearth and
home, their women and children.
Does that mean they
will be granted leave
to defend their homes if
the settlements are attacked?
Of course.
You got yourself
a colonial militia, General.
It is
what we wanted.
Major Duncan
Heyward reporting, sir,
en route to Fort William
Henry and bearing dispatches.
Safe journey,
I trust?
Yes, and I didn't
experience anything
so surprising from
Bristol to Albany
as that that I
witnessed here today.
And what was that?
The Crown negotiating
the terms of service.
I know.
One has to reason with these
colonials to get them to do anything.
Tiring, isn't it? But
that's the lay of the land.
I thought British policy is
"Make the world England," sir.
I see you're to serve with
the 35th Regiment of Foot
at Fort William Henry
under Colonel Munro.
I’ll be marching
the 60th to Fort Edward.
Explain to the Major,
he has little to fear
from this General Marquis de
Montcalm in the first place,
and therefore scant need of a
colonial militia in the second,
because the French
haven't the nature for war.
Their Latinate
voluptuousness
combines with their Gallic
laziness. And the result is,
they'd rather eat and make love
with their faces than fight.
Might I inquire if
General Webb has heard
from Colonel Munro's
daughters?
I was to rendezvous with them in
Albany and escort them to the fort, sir.
You there, what does Munro call you?
The Scotsman has sent you one of
his Mohawk allies to guide you.
Magua.
The Scotsman's daughters
are at the Poltroon's house.
A company of the 60th
will accompany you,
and Magua will
show you the way.
Dawn. At the encampment, 6:00 a.
m. sharp. See to it you're there.
I’ll take him
for you, sir.
Cora.
Duncan!
How long have
you been in Albany?
For days and days.
And yourself?
Just arrived.
By God,
it's good to see you.
I don't know
what to say, Duncan.
I truly wish they did,
but my feelings don't...
Don't go beyond friendship.
Don't you see?
Respect and friendship.
Isn't that a reasonable basis for
a man and a woman to be married?
And all else
may grow in time?
Some say
that's the way of it.
Some?
Cousin Eugenie,
my father...
Well, then, Cora.
In my heart I know,
once we're joined,
we'll be the most
marvelous couple in London.
I’m certain of that.
So why not let those whom
you trust, your father,
help settle
what's best for you?
In view of your indecision, you
should rely on their judgment.
And mine.
Will you
consider that?
Please consider that.
Yes.
Yes, I will.
Duncan!
By God,
you've grown up.
We leave
in the morning?
Yes, miss.
I shan't
sleep tonight.
What an adventure. Have
you seen the red men?
A few.
I absolutely cannot wait
to return to Portman Square,
having been
to the wilderness.
It's so exciting,
Duncan.
Alice?
Can we rest soon?
Absolutely.
You, there.
Scout, we must stop soon.
Women are tired.
Not here. Two leagues.
Better water. We stop there.
No, stop in the
glade just ahead.
When the ladies are rested, we
will proceed. Do you understand?
Excuse me.
What did you say?
Magua said,
understand English very well.
Hold tight!
Come on!
Right! To the right!
Prepare your firearms!
As three ranks!
Make ready!
First and second rank,
present!
Fire!
No, Duncan.
In case your aim's any
better than your judgment.
Your wounded should try
walking on back to Albany.
They'll never
make a passage north.
Stop it! Stop it! We
need them to get out!
Why's he
loosing the horses?
Why don't you ask him?
Too easy to track.
They'll be heard for miles.
We were headed to
Fort William Henry.
We'll take you
as far as the fort.
We're walking
out of here fast.
Unless all of you'd rather wait for
the next Huron war party to come by.
Scout, I’d like to
thank you for your help.
How much
further is it?
Night and a bit.
Appears we're
well away from them.
Maybe.
Maybe they ain't alone.
That Huron captain
back there...
The guide?
He's a Mohawk.
No Mohawk.
He's Huron.
What reason did he have
to murder the girl?
What?
The dark-haired one.
Miss Cora Munro?
Murder her?
He never set eyes on her before
today. She's only been here a week.
Blood vengeance?
A reproach or insult?
Of course not!
How is it
you were so nearby?
Came across the war party. Tracked them.
Then you're assigned
to Fort William Henry?
No.
Fort Edward then?
Heading west
to Can-tuck-ee.
There is a war on. How is
it you are heading west?
Well, we kind of
face to the north,
and real sudden-like,
turn left.
I thought all our colonial
scouts were in the militia.
The militia is fighting
the French in the north!
I ain't your scout. And we
sure ain't in no damn militia.
Ottawa, two français.
What did
you say?
Mirrors,
tools,
the clothes.
Everything
was inside.
They didn't
take anything.
And moving fast.
And a war party.
Let us look after them.
Leave them.
Whoever they are,
though they're strangers,
they're at least entitled
to a Christian burial.
They can't
be left behind.
Let us go, miss.
I will not! I’ve seen the
face of war before, sir,
but I’ve not seen war made
upon women and children.
And almost as cruel
is your indifference.
Miss Munro,
they're not strangers.
And they stay
as they lay.
Why didn't you
bury those people?
Anyone looking for our trail would
see it as a sign we passed that way.
You knew them well?
You were acting for our
benefit, and I apologize.
I misunderstood you.
Well, that's
to be expected.
My father
warned me about...
Your father?
Chingachgook. He warned
me about people like you.
Oh, he did?
He said, "Do not try
to understand them. "
Yes. And, "Do not try to
make them understand you.
"That is because they are a
breed apart and make no sense. "
Why did
they turn back?
Burial ground.
"Breed apart.
We make no sense?"
In your particular case,
miss, I’d make allowance.
Thank you so much.
Where is
your real family?
They buried my ma and pa and my sisters.
Chingachgook found me
with two French trappers,
raised me up
as his own.
I’m sorry.
I do not remember.
I wasn't but one or two.
How did you
learn English?
My father sent Uncas and I to Reverend
Wheelock's school when I was 10.
Why were those people living
in this defenseless place?
After seven years
indentured service
in Virginia,
they headed out here
'cause the frontier's the only
land available to poor people.
Out here,
they're beholden to none.
Not living by
another's leave.
The name was Cameron.
John and
Alexandra Cameron.
My father's people say that
at the birth of the sun,
and of his brother, the
moon, their mother died.
So the sun gave
to the earth her body,
from which was
to spring all life.
And he drew forth from
her breast the stars.
The stars, he threw into the night
sky to remind him of her soul.
So there's the
Camerons' monument.
My folks' too,
I guess.
You are right, Mr. Poe.
We do not understand
what is happening here.
And it's not as I imagined it would be,
thinking of it
in Boston and London.
Sorry to
disappoint you.
No, on the contrary.
It is more deeply stirring to my blood
than any imagining
could possibly have been.
Top of the next ridge.
The fort's downhill of it.
The men of the regiment will
fetch water from the lake,
build fires, and provide
every comfort and desire.
I cannot wait
to see Papa.
Fire!
Prepare! Point! Fire!
Open up.
I’m Major Duncan Heyward.
Captain Jeffrey Beams.
Didn't expect you
to make it through.
Let's go
to Munro.
Hello, boys!
Nathaniel!
I need to talk
to you, Jack.
Uncas! Thought you and
Nathaniel weren't joining up.
We didn't.
Papa! Papa!
Alice! Cora!
Why are you here?
And where the hell
are my reinforcements?
Get Mr. Phelps.
Told you to stay away. Why
did you disobey me, girls?
When? How? I...
My letter.
There was none.
What?
There was no letter.
I sent three couriers
to Webb.
One called
Magua arrived.
He delivered
no such message.
Does Webb not even know
we are besieged?
Sir, Webb has no idea.
And he certainly does not
know to send reinforcements.
What happened to you?
On the George Road.
Attacked.
We're fine.
Are you all right?
Yes.
What will happen
here, Papa?
We'll be all right, girl.
This Magua led us into it.
Eighteen killed.
These men came to our aid.
They guided us here.
Thank you.
Do you need anything?
Help ourselves to a few
horns from your powder stores.
Some food.
Indebted to you.
Miss Cora,
how are you?
Hello, Mr. Phelps.
Mrs. McCann will get
some dry clothes for you.
Thank you.
Go with
your sister, Alice.
It'll be all right, girl.
It’ll be all right.
Might I inquire
after the situation, sir,
given that I’ve seen the French
engineering from the ridge above?
The situation is, his guns are bigger
than mine and he has more of them.
We keep our heads down while his
troops dig 30 yards of trench a day.
When those trenches are 200 yards
from the fort and within range,
he'll bring in
his 15-inch mortars,
lob explosive rounds over our
walls and pound us to dust.
They look to be
300 yards out.
If they're digging 30 yards
a day, you have three days.
Damn. Damn.
This man here can make a
run straight through to Webb.
Three days is not enough time to get
to Albany and back with reinforcements.
Webb's not in Albany. He marched
the 60th to Fort Edward two days ago.
Webb is at Edward?
Yes, sir.
That's only
12 miles away.
He could have reinforcements
here the day after tomorrow.
You, sir, pick your man. Major
Heyward will provide a diversion.
I’ll draft out
a dispatch.
Captain Beams will seek you
out and give it to you later.
Something else. Cameron's
cabin. Frontier cabin.
Came upon it yesterday. It was
burnt out, everyone murdered.
It was Ottawa,
allied to the French.
Aye.
So?
It was a war party.
That means they're gonna be
attacking up and down the frontier.
Thank you, sir.
People here, Mohawks,
settlers, have family out there.
That'll be all, sir!
Things were done.
Nobody was spared.
Those considerations are subordinate
to the interests of the Crown.
A terrible feature of war here
in the Americas, Major Heyward.
Best keep your eye fixed on
our duty, to defeat France.
That hangs on
a courier to Webb.
For my children are the
children of the true faith.
My friendship and esteem is boundless.
Tomorrow, I will sing
the war song with you
at the great
council fire.
Magua, how are things
with your English friends?
We're at one.
Join us.
Hear what Le Subtil
has to tell us.
The English war chief, Webb, goes
to Fort Edward with 60th Regiment.
He does not know that my father's
army attacks Fort William Henry.
Magua was successful?
The other two couriers
died in the forest.
By now, Munro would know his
dispatch did not get through.
He'll send another.
Grey Hair will try.
Four or five, including
two women, entered the fort.
The Grey Hair's children
were under Magua's knife.
They escaped.
They will be
under it again.
Why do you hate
the Grey Hair, Magua?
When the Grey Hair is dead,
Magua will eat his heart.
Before he dies,
Magua will put his children
under the knife,
so the Grey Hair will know
his seed is wiped out forever.
My engineers are advancing
the trench through the night.
You may have
your opportunity soon.
Miss Cora.
Gentleman
looking for you.
Miss Munro.
Hello.
May I?
It will seep, and then
it's going to draw.
Thank you, miss.
About done holding
hands with Miss Munro?
We got some work to do.
What are you
looking at, sir?
I’m looking at you, miss.
Munro refused to
believe what happened.
He does not even
want to hear it.
Well, he's gonna have to.
Get together by
the west bastion.
Ian, Sharitarish,
Ongewasgone and William.
Tight weave?
Silk.
Another 40 yards.
And how am I to know it wasn't
a raid by common thieves?
The cabin was attacked by a war
party fighting with the French.
They're sweeping south
down the frontier
attacking farms
and Mohawk villages.
All the men
are stuck here.
I need proof more convincing
than this man's opinion,
before I weaken the fort's
defenses by releasing the militia.
Chingachgook's of the same
opinion about the raid.
Taken together,
that's gospel.
Your fort will stand or fall
depending on Webb's reinforcements,
not the presence
of the colonials.
I judge military matters here, not you.
Your judgment is not more
important than their right,
under agreement with Webb to
defend their farms and families.
Major Heyward was there. He was at
John Cameron's. He saw what it was.
What exactly
did you see, Major?
I saw nothing
that would lead me
to the conclusion
it was other than a raid
by savages
bent on thievery.
You're a liar!
Major!
Montcalm is a soldier and
a gentleman, not a butcher.
Easy for you to suppose.
It’s their women and children
alone on the farms, not yours!
You forget
yourself, sir!
We're not forgetting
Webb's promise.
British promises are honored, and
the militia will not be released,
because I need more definite
proof than this man's word!
Nathaniel's word's been
good on this frontier
a long time
before you got here.
This meeting is over!
The militia stays.
Does the rule of English
law no longer govern?
Has it been replaced
by absolutism?
If English law
cannot be trusted,
maybe these people
would do better
making their own peace
with the French.
That is sedition!
That is the truth!
I’ll have you beaten
from this fort.
Someday I think you and I are
gonna have a serious disagreement.
Anyone fomenting on advocating
the leaving of Fort William Henry
will be hung
for sedition.
Anyone actually caught leaving
will be shot for desertion.
My decision is final!
Get out.
Cora?
I wanted to
talk to you.
Talk with Duncan, Cora.
I must manage. I cannot
be an invalid schoolgirl.
Alice.
I’ll see if Mr. Phelps
needs anything.
I’m sorry.
I didn't mean to...
Cora, when we come
together back in England
and are married and
away from this place,
what had to be done and said
here will matter not at all.
I’m certain of that.
Duncan,
I promised you an answer.
You've complimented me with
your persistence and patience.
But the decision
I have come to
is that I’d rather make
the gravest of mistakes
than to surrender
my own judgment.
Please take this
as my final answer.
It must be no.
I see.
Yeah, Nathaniel, but you
weren't ever for being here.
That's right. I saw it that way
then and I see it that way now.
Ian, if I had kin
in the settlements,
hell be damn sure
I’d be long gone.
What do we do about
being under Crown law?
I believe if they set aside
their law as and when they wish,
their law no longer has
rightful authority over us.
All they have over us
then is tyranny.
And I will not live
under that yoke.
So I will stay
here no longer.
Anyone caught leaving
the fort could be shot,
so each man make
your own decision.
Those who are going,
be back in an hour.
Out the northern
sally port.
Strike for the east side of the swamp
till you clear
the French picket line.
Head north over the ridge,
then come about southeast.
Fork left in Little Meadow and you're
free of the outpost and skirmishes.
Should've gotten
out of this long ago.
Got no families, Captain.
Figured we'd stay and give a hand.
I’ll cover you from
the top of the bastion.
You're not
coming with us?
I got
a reason to stay.
That reason wear a striped
skirt and work in the surgery?
It does.
No offense, but it's a better-looking
reason than you, Jack Winthrop.
Push hard, 'cause you got to
clear the French outpost by dawn.
Good luck, Jack.
Ongewasgone,
are you staying?
Yes.
There's too many French.
And so few
of us to fight.
Not too many to die. But we've given
our word to our English fathers.
You, sir!
As you were!
Stand off.
Take him.
As you were.
He saved us. We're alive
only because of him.
The man encouraged
the colonials to desert,
in this very room,
and in my presence.
Sir.
He is guilty of sedition.
He must be tried and hanged
like any other criminal,
regardless of what
he did for my children.
But he knew the
consequences and he stayed.
Are those the actions
of a criminal?
Duncan, do something.
He knew the penalty
for his actions.
He ought to pay without
sending you to beg.
You know he wouldn't send me.
You falsely spoke of what you saw.
What happened at the farm
was as Nathaniel said.
But not with enough certainty to
outweigh British interests in this fort.
And who empowered these
colonials to pass judgment
on England's policies
in her own possessions,
and to come and go without
so much as a "By your leave"?
They do not live
their lives by your leave!
They hack it out of the wilderness
with their own two hands,
bearing their children
along the way.
You are defending him because
you've become infatuated with him!
Duncan, you are a man with
a few admirable qualities.
But taken as a whole, I was wrong
to have thought so highly of you.
Cora!
Cora, I would do anything I
could to keep you from being hurt.
But this man is guilty of sedition
and subject to military
justice and beyond pardon.
Justice?
If that's justice,
then the sooner French guns blow
the English army out of America,
the better it will be
for the people here.
You do not know what
you're saying! Yes, I do.
I know exactly
what I’m saying!
And if it is sedition, then
I am guilty of sedition too.
They're going to
hang you.
Why didn't you leave
when you had the chance?
Because what I’m
interested in is right here.
What can I do?
Webb's reinforcements
will arrive or not.
If they do not arrive, the
fort will fall to the French.
If that happens, stay
close to your father.
Stay close to him.
The French officers will try to
protect the officers among the English.
No. I will find you.
Do not.
Promise me.
The whole world's
on fire.
What is it?
Remember
what I told you.
Stay close to your
father and the officers.
Colonel Munro, I have known
you as a gallant antagonist.
I am happy to make your
acquaintance as a friend.
And I yours,
monsieur Le Marquis.
Please accept
my compliments
for the strong and skillful
defense of your fortress.
Under the command
of a lesser man,
it would have
fallen long ago,
given the superior
numbers and materials.
Chance has allowed me
to array against you.
Monsieur Le Marquis, I am
a soldier, not a diplomat.
You called this parley
for a better reason
than an exchange
of compliments.
You have already done everything which
is necessary for the honor of your prince.
But now I beg you to listen to
the admonishments of humanity.
I beg you to consider my
terms for your surrender.
Perhaps the general's glass
can reach as far as the Hudson
and seize the size and
eminence of the army of Webb?
My scouts intercepted this
dispatch intended for you.
Capitaine de Bougainville.
"To Colonel Munro.
Sir, I regret to inform you
"that I have no men available
to send to your rescue.
"It is quite impossible.
"I advise you to seek
terms for surrender.
"I remain. Jerome Webb at Fort Edward. "
This is the signature of Webb.
And I know the temper of our men.
Rather than spend the war in a
French prison hulk in Hudson Bay,
they'd fight
to the end.
You've had your answer,
monsieur Le Marquis.
Sir, I beg you not to sign
the death warrant of so many
until you have listened
to what I have to say.
Go on.
None of your men will see
the inside of a prison barge.
They are free, so long
as they return to England
and fight no more
on this continent,
and the civilian militia
return to their farms.
Their arms?
They may leave
the fortress fully armed.
My colors?
Carry them to England
with pride.
Allow me to consult
with my officers.
I have lived to see something
which I never expected.
A British officer
afraid to support another.
Webb can
burn in hell.
And we'll go back and dig our
graves behind those ramparts.
Death and honor are
thought to be the same,
but today I have learned
that sometimes they are not.
Sir...
Monsieur Le Marquis,
I am deeply touched
by such unusual and
unexpected generosity.
My fort is yours
under the condition
that I be given till dawn
to bury my dead,
to prepare my men and women
for the long journey ahead
and to hand my wounded
over to your surgeons.
Granted, monsieur.
Is the hatchet buried between
the English and my French father?
Yes.
Not a warrior has a scalp and
the white men become friends.
My master
owns these lands,
and I have been ordered to
drive off the English squatters.
They have
consented to go,
so now I call them
enemies no longer.
Magua took the hatchet
to color with blood.
It’s still bright.
Only when it's red,
then it will be buried.
So many suns have set since
Magua struck the war post.
And where is that sun?
Magua is the son
of his people
and he has come
to lead many of them.
But Magua has power with his
Huron people and others here,
I know well.
Magua's village
and lodges were burnt.
Magua's children were
killed by the English.
I was taken as slave by the Mohawk
who fought for the Grey Hair.
Magua's wife
believed he was dead
and became
the wife of another.
The Grey Hair was the
father of all that.
In time,
Magua became blood brother
to the Mohawk to become free.
But always in his heart,
he is Huron.
And his heart will be
whole again on the day
the Grey Hair and
all his seed are dead.
Does the chief of the Canadas believe
the English will keep the terms?
I fear having let them go, which I must,
I will only fight the same men
again when I drive towards Albany.
But I cannot break the
term of the surrender
and sully
the lilies of France.
Monsieur,
the fort is yours.
Left three ranks,
make ready!
Aim, set.
Fire!
Present, fire!
Full company!
Grey Hair,
before you die,
know that I will put under
the knife your children,
so I will wipe your seed
from the Earth forever.
Leave her alone!
When you fall into British hands
again, I’ll have you hanged!
Faster!
Head to the river!
Where are we going?
Nowhere.
I don't understand.
This is as far
as we go.
If we're lucky,
they'll figure we beached
our canoes and
headed cross land.
If we're very lucky, they'll
figure we went over the falls.
Our only hope is
that they pass us by.
If they do?
Take the south rim
down the mountain.
It’s 12 miles cross
country to Fort Edward.
And if they don't?
You'll just have to forego
the pleasure of hanging me.
Powder?
Gone.
Mine's soaking wet!
Our father...
Did you see my father?
From a distance.
Say nothing to Alice.
Get back!
Yes! Go ahead!
What the bloody hell
plan is this?
I want you to go!
If we go, there's a chance
there won't be a fight.
There's no powder. If we don't
go in that, there's no chance.
None! You understand?
Coward!
You've done everything
you can do. Save yourself!
If the worst happens...
You stay alive!
If they don't kill you, they'll
take you north up to the Huron lands.
Submit, do you hear?
You're strong. You survive!
You stay alive,
no matter what occurs!
I will find you,
no matter how long it
takes, no matter how far!
I will find you.
I don't speak Huron. Do
you speak French, Major?
Yes.
Translate for me into French
every word as I say it.
I come to you unarmed and in
peace to unstuff your ears, Sachem.
Let the children of the
dead Colonel Munro go free.
Take fire out of
the English anger
over the murder of
their helpless ones.
Sachem, the French fathers
made peace. Magua broke it.
It is false that the French will
be friends still to the Huron.
Would Magua use the ways of
les français and the Yengeese?
Would you?
Yes!
Would the Huron make his Algonquin
brothers foolish with brandy
and steal his lands to sell
them for gold to the white man?
Would Huron have greed for
more land than a man can use?
Would Huron fool Seneca
into taking
all the furs of all the
animals of the forest
for beads
and strong whiskey?
Those are the ways of the
Yengeese and the français traders
and their masters in Europe
infected with the sickness of greed.
Magua's heart
is twisted.
He would make himself
into what twisted him.
I am Nathaniel
of the Yengeese.
Hawkeye, adopted son of
Chingachgook of the Mohican people.
Let the children
of the dead Munro
and the Yengeese officer
go free.
This belt, which is a record of the days
of my father's people,
speaks for my truth.
Tell him I’ll trade him.
Me for her! Say it.
Stop it!
I am La Longue Carabine!
My death is a great honor
to the Huron! Take me!
Did you tell him?
Yes.
Stop!
I said
to take me.
Take me!
My compliments, sir.
Take her and get out!
Duncan... What are they doing
to Duncan? Where's Alice?
Alice!
Uncas!
Great Spirit and
maker of all life,
a warrior goes to
you swift and straight
as an arrow
shot into the sun.
Welcome him, and let him take his place
at the council fire
of my people.
He is Uncas,
my son.
Tell him to be patient
and ask death for speed,
for they are
all there but one,
I, Chingachgook,
the last of the Mohicans.